Evgenia Komleva

Email: komleva.ep@phystech.edu linkedin.com/EvgeniaKomleva Have UK work permit visa

Developer with 3+ years of R&D experience in deep learning and its applications. Worked a lot with natural language processing (NLP), computer vision (CV) and multimodal models.

EXPERIENCE

ABBYY Moscow

Part-time, Mar 2021 - Jan 2023

Part-time, Sep 2020 - now

Russia. MOSCOW

Russia, MOSCOW

Aug 2021 - Aug 2023

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

NLP Engineer

- Model fine-tune in https://www.abbyy/flexicapture/
- Clustering queries using BERT and different linear models
- Date and person recognition
- Multi-Page Document Classification
- Solved Visual Question Answering task with different models: OFA, mDETR, CLIP+YOLOR

DRIVECAST MOSCOW

Middle Computer Vision Engineer

• Deployed Python API This is a sample text in blue.for transform 2d human pose to 3d

Impact: You can see demo here: demo

• Detection of safety equipment at work (masks, helmets, gloves)

Impact: Research papers, fine-tune YOLOv5, demo is available here: https://youtu.be/9DaAAI1OT8s

- Make custom object recognition model using YOLOv5
- Race car team identification from helicopter video and team identification
- Experience with general machine learning tools to build models and analyze data using Python

ROSSELKHOZBANK Moscow Part-time, Jul 2020 - Mar 2021 Research Intern

Solved the problem of pre-moderation of the text using the model BERT

- Solved the problem of pre-moderation of images using the model Resnet-50
- Designed a model to predict churn

EDUCATION

MOSCOW INSTITUTE OF PHYSICS AND TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor of Computer Science specialization in Artificial Intelligence **Thesis:** Sentence Simplification for Russian using Transfer Learning

SKOLTECH Russia, MOSCOW Master's degree specialization in Data Science Aug 2021 - Aug 2023

MOSCOW INSTITUTE OF PHYSICS AND TECHNOLOGY

Master of Computer Science specialization in Artificial Intelligence

PUBLICATIONS

- A Differentiable Language Model Adversarial Attack on Text Classifiers https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document
- Sentence Simplification for Russian using Transfer Learning http://www.dialog-21.ru/komlevaepplusanastasyevdg157.pdf
- Human pose estimation (page 284) https:/compressed2.pdf

PROJECTS

- Text Simplification using mBART network https://github.com/EvgeniaKomleva/SimplifyWithMuss.git
- Style Transfer Bot https://github.com/EvgeniaKomleva/StyleTransferBot

SKILLS

- Sciences: ML, DL, probability theory, linear algebra
- Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX
- Other Technologies: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, GIT, numpy, scikit-learn, pandas, matplotlib

ACHIEVEMENTS

3 place in Toloka Visual Question Answering Challenge (WSDM Cup 2023)
https://codalab/competitions/7434
Victory in the competition of scientific works (https://conf.mipt.ru/conference-total)
Deep Learning School (2nd degree) https://drive.google.com/diplom
TEACHING
Teaching Assistant at Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology
Deep learning for NLP course
One of the ML course writers https://youtu.be/tiser